Luther Henderson Papers
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1940s-2002 (Box 1-94, 126-127)
  - Performer Projects
    - Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, 1987-1988
      - Quelquechose suite: op. 2. Me and my girl medley
        - Scores (Box-folder 83/4)
    - Shore, Dinah, undated
      - Scores (Box-folder 72/6)
    - Uggams, Leslie, 1996
      - Scores and correspondence (Box-folder 72/7-8)
  - Luther Henderson Songbook
    Scores and lead sheets, most of which were intended for future publication as bound volumes. Includes both vocal and instrumental works.
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Accelerator and Don't sing it (Box-folder 84/1)
    - All for Harold (That's my boy!) (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Andante, op. 2 (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Baby blue (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Be a girl (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Blue legato brass (Box-folder 84/1)
    - The blues (Box-folder 84/1)
    - The bossa cha-cha nova (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Bossa nova: op. 1 (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Bossa nova: op. 2 (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Call it love (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Can't stop (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Chicago (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Chicken reel (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Cloak and dagger (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Clockwise permutation (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Crystal tree (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Darling (Box-folder 84/2)
    - The devil you say (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Don't mess with Tess (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Doxology for my teeny bopper: op. 1 (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Doxology for my teeny bopper: op. 2 (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Dream smoke (Box-folder 84/2)
    - A drum is a woman (Box-folder 84/2)
    - The evil eye (Box-folder 84/2)
    - For the homeless (Box-folder 84/2)
    - For the Lord (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Fox trot (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Frankie and Johnny twist (Box-folder 84/2)
    - The future Mrs. (Mr.) me (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Give me a man (Box-folder 84/2)
    - A gospel wedding song (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Got no time (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Gotta have talent (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Hey Cherie! (Box-folder 84/2)
    - High hat (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Home is the entire world (Box-folder 84/2)
    - I know her name (Box-folder 84/2)
    - If I could fly (Box-folder 84/2)
    - India inck (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Just got me (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Lady of the lavender mist (Box-folder 84/3)
    - The Lord is my shepherd (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Love has a funny way (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Love scene (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Love song (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Love stays (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Lullaby (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Lutu's song (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Magical man (Box-folder 84/3)
    - March time (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Margo's tune (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Meditation (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Melanie's lullaby (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Melanie's marching song (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Mercy me (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Minuet in blue-hoo (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Mutual funds (Box-folder 84/3)
    - My gray matter (Box-folder 84/3)
    - My kind of love (Box-folder 84/3)
    - My love (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Not your heart (Box-folder 84/4)
    - Nothin' funny (Box-folder 84/4)
    - No wonder (Box-folder 84/4)
    - Oh God (Box-folder 84/4)
    - Old MacDonald's farm (Box-folder 84/4)
    - Opus staccato (Box-folder 84/4)
    - Please don't go away from me (Box-folder 84/4)
    - River song (Box-folder 84/4)
    - The saga of Bailey (Box-folder 85/1)
    - Satin-skinned gal (Box-folder 85/1)
    - September theme (Box-folder 85/1)
    - Small aria (Box-folder 85/1)
    - So what (Box-folder 85/1)
    - Solitaire (Box-folder 85/1)
    - Solo and duet (Box-folder 85/1)
    - Sorrow (Box-folder 85/1)
    - The Soulville train (Box-folder 85/1)
    - The spelling bee (Box-folder 85/1)
    - Spell it out (Box-folder 85/1)
    - Stanley (Box-folder 85/1)
    - Stephanie (Box-folder 85/1)
    - Sweet little baby of mine (Box-folder 85/1)
    - Sweet Mary (Box-folder 85/1)
    - Take his hand (Box-folder 85/2)
    - Take my hand (Box-folder 85/2)
    - Ten good years (Box-folder 85/2)
    - Thanksgiving (Box-folder 85/2)
    - That's life, I guess (Box-folder 85/2)
    - That's no news (Box-folder 85/2)
    - There's a look to her (Box-folder 85/2)
    - There's something about a man who doesn't love you (Box-folder 85/2)
    - This land (Box-folder 85/2)
    - The time is wrong (Box-folder 85/2)
    - Theme (Box-folder 85/2)
    - To a tilted em (Box-folder 85/2)
    - The torque (Box-folder 85/2)
    - Travel on (Box-folder 85/2)
    - A tune for WM. S. (Box-folder 85/2)
    - Waltz in E♭ (Box-folder 85/3)
    - Watergate watchman (Box-folder 85/3)
    - Well, well (Box-folder 85/3)
    - What a day (Box-folder 85/3)
    - What a star can do (Box-folder 85/3)
    - What ever happened to the dream (Box-folder 85/3)
    - What ev'ry woman knows (Box-folder 85/3)
    - What happened (Box-folder 85/3)
    - What I'm gonna do (Box-folder 85/3)
    - What kind of jazz is that? (Box-folder 85/3)
    - White of her (Box-folder 85/3)
    - Wiggins (Box-folder 85/3)
    - Woman (Box-folder 85/3)
    - Yesterday's child (Box-folder 85/3)
    - You (Box-folder 85/3)
    - You name it (Box-folder 85/3)
    - Young man (Box-folder 85/3)
    - Lists of songs for inclusion (Box-folder 85/4)
  - Music Library Files
    Annotated scores and lists of materials in Henderson's library.
    Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Beane, Reginald (Box-folder 85/5)
    - Bells are ringing (Box-folder 85/6)
    - Blackwell, Charles and Herb Schultz (Box-folder 86/1-3)
    - Christmas songs (Box-folder 86/4)
    - Do re mi, Includes a complete piano-conductor score (Box-folder 86/5, 87/1-3)
    - Flora and the red menace (Box-folder 87/4)
    - Hallelujah baby! (Box-folder 87/5-7)
    - Lists of sheet music in library (Box-folder 88/1)
    - Masello, Robert and Peter Strode (Box-folder 88/2)
    - Miscellanous songs, Arranged by composer (Box-folder 88/3-7)
    - Miss Ethel Waters (Box-folder 89/1)
    - Morgan, Bob (Box-folder 89/2)
    - Rodgers and Hart (Box-folder 89/3)
    - Strayhorn, Billy (Box-folder 89/4)
    - Tempo Music Inc., Mostly Duke Ellington scores (Box-folder 89/5)
    - That 5 a.m. jazz (Box-folder 89/6)
  - Brick Fleagle Music
    Scores and parts by Henderson's close friend and fellow arranger, Jacob Roger "Brick" Fleagle. Includes arrangements by other composers in Fleagle's hand.
    - Ain't cha-glad? (Box-folder 90/1)
    - Alice blue gown (Box-folder 90/2)
    - Auld lang syne (Box-folder 90/3)
    - Basin Street blues, Arranged by Ken Macomber (Box-folder 90/4)
    - Blue interlude, Arranged by Benny Carter (Box-folder 90/5)
    - Blue Lou, Arranged by Horace Henderson (Box-folder 90/6)
    - Blue room, Arranged by A.G. Williams (Box-folder 90/7)
    - Burnin' de candle at both end (Box-folder 90/8)
    - Can't we be friends, Arranged by Benny Carter (Box-folder 90/9)
    - Chocolate (Box-folder 90/10)
    - Ciao (Box-folder 90/11)
    - D♮ blues (Box-folder 91/1)
    - Dark eyes (Box-folder 91/2)
    - Dear old Southland, Arranged by A.G. Williams (Box-folder 91/3)
    - The Duke steps out, Arranged by A.G. Williams (Box-folder 91/4)
    - An earful of music, Arranged by Benny Carter (Box-folder 91/5)
    - Gee! Ain't I good to you, Arranged by Bill Long (Box-folder 91/6)
    - Heavy Edna, Arranged by Joe St. John (Box-folder 91/7)
    - Hot Toddy, Arranged by Benny Carter (Box-folder 91/8)
    - I found a new baby, Arranged by Joe St. John (Box-folder 91/9)
    - I got rhythm (Box-folder 91/10)
    - I know that you know, Arranged by Horace Henderson (Box-folder 92/1)
    - I never slept a wink last night (Box-folder 92/2)
    - I'm comin' Virginia (Box-folder 92/3)
    - Juba dance, Arranged by Paul Alspach (Box-folder 92/4)
    - Lady be good, Arranged by Mat Van Cleave (Box-folder 92/5)
    - Liza, Arranged by Benny Carter (Box-folder 92/6)
    - Makin' friends (Box-folder 92/7)
    - The man from the South, Arranged by Red Kent (Box-folder 92/8)
    - Mandy, Arranged by Benny Carter (Box-folder 92/9)
    - My gal Sal, Arranged by Fletcher Henderson (Box-folder 92/10)
    - Nagasaki, Arranged by Benny Carter (Box-folder 93/1)
    - Nola (Box-folder 93/2)
    - Oh! Miss Hannah! (Box-folder 93/3)
    - Old loves (Box-folder 93/4)
    - Red Bean Row, Arranged by Nat Leslie (Box-folder 93/5)
    - Riff romp, Arranged by Benny Carter (Box-folder 93/6)
    - Rockin' in rhythm, Arranged by A.G. Williams (Box-folder 93/7)
    - Rolling in love (Box-folder 93/8)
    - Royal garden blues, Arranged by Nat Leslie (Box-folder 93/9)
    - Shanghai shuffle, Arranged by Fletcher Henderson (Box-folder 93/10)
    - Somebody loves me, Arranged by Bill Long (Box-folder 94/1)
    - Sophisticated lady (Box-folder 94/2)
    - Spellbound, Arranged by Benny Carter (Box-folder 94/3)
    - Star dust (Box-folder 94/4)
    - Sweet Sue (Box-folder 94/5)
    - Swing it, Arranged by Benny Carter (Box-folder 94/6)
    - Swing low, sweet chariot (Box-folder 94/7)
    - Three little words (Box-folder 94/8)
    - Tired of everything (Box-folder 94/9)
    - Was my face red? (Box-folder 94/10)
    - When Bhudda smiles, Arranged by "Hap" Wolff (Box-folder 94/11)
    - Who cares?, Arranged by C.L. Johnson (Box-folder 94/12)
    - Will you, won't you, be my baby? (Box-folder 94/13)
- Subject Files, 1960-2002 (Box 95-115)
  Business papers, scripts, contracts, programs, clippings, financial documents, and/or notes. All projects are musical theater productions or concert works unless indicated otherwise.
  Organized in two subseries: general projects and performer projects. Arranged alphabetically by title of project or last name of performer.
  - General Projects
    - About face, undated, Script only (Box-folder 95/1)
    - Ain't misbehavin, 1978, 1988 (Box-folder 95/2-9, 96/1-5)
    - Belle Starr, 1996, By Charles Burr; Script only (Box-folder 96/6)
    - Billy Taylor's 80th birthday celebration [concert], 2002 (Box-folder 96/7)
    - Black and blue, 1989 (Box-folder 96/8)
    - Blind man of Broadway, 1991, Script only (Box-folder 97/1-2)
    - Bojangles, undated, Script only (Box-folder 97/3)
    - Carver, undated, Script only (Box-folder 97/4)
    - Celluloid, 1978, Script only (Box-folder 97/5)
    - The chit'lin circuit, 1985, Script only (Box-folder 97/6)
    - Classic Ellington [concert/recording], 1999, 2000 (Box-folder 97/7-8, 98/1-8)
    - Conquering Thursday, 1969 (Box-folder 98/9)
    - The crystal tree, 1981 (Box-folder 98/10-13)
    - Do re mi, 1960 (Box-folder 99/1)
    - Eliza [WNET film], 1975 (Box-folder 99/2)
    - Ella Fitzgerald 75th birthday celebration, 1993, Script only (Box-folder 99/3)
    - Ellington: a theatrical review, 1978 (Box-folder 99/4)
    - Ellington centennial [UCLA concert], 1999 (Box-folder 99/5-7)
    - Ellington suite, 1991 (Box-folder 99/8)
    - Ellington's New York [concert], 1993 (Box-folder 99/9)
    - F. Jasmine Addams, 1971 (Box-folder 99/10)
      Script only
    - Far East suite [recording project], 1999 see Classic Ellington
    - The first, 1981 (Box-folder 100/1-2)
    - Fresh air taxi, 1990, Script only (Box-folder 100/3)
    - Getting up nights, undated, By Charles Burr; Script only (Box-folder 100/4)
    - Good news, 1973 (Box-folder 100/5)
    - Hallelujah baby!, undated, Script only (Box-folder 100/6)
    - Happy New Year, 1980, Script only (Box-folder 100/7)
    - Hey, foxy mama, 1987 (Box-folder 101/1-3)
    - Hot feet, 2002, Script only (Box-folder 101/4)
    - Hot spot, 1963, Script only (Box-folder 101/5)
    - Jelly's last jam, 1992
      - Business papers (Box-folder 101/6-9, 102/1-4)
      - Clearance forms (Box-folder 102/5)
      - Clippings (Box-folder 102/6-8, 103/1-5)
      - Programs (Box-folder 103/6)
      - Royalty statements (Box-folder 103/7-8, 104/1-6)
      - Scripts (Box-folder 105/1-7, 106/1-3)
      - Student study guide (Box-folder 106/4)
      - Tour materials (Box-folder 106/5-6)
    - Keep a knockin', 1988, Script only (Box-folder 106/7)
    - Laura, undated, Script only (Box-folder 106/8)
    - Little ham, 1987 (Box-folder 106/9)
    - Look to the rainbow, 1985 (Box-folder 106/10)
    - Lucky guy, undated, Script only (Box-folder 106/11)
    - Lush life: a Strayhorn cabaret [recording project], 1998 (Box-folder 106/12)
    - Mahalia, 1978 (Box-folder 107/1)
    - Marilyn, undated, Script only (Box-folder 107/2)
    - The mayor of Harlem, undated (Box-folder 107/3-4)
    - Me and Wilhelmina, undated (Box-folder 107/5)
    - Miss Ethel Waters, 1983 (Box-folder 107/6)
    - Miss Teen USA, 1986 (Box-folder 107/7)
    - MLK suite, 1992 (Box-folder 107/8)
    - Mr. Nobody, undated, Script only (Box-folder 107/9)
    - My Broadway [concert], 1998 (Box-folder 107/10)
    - My mother's daughter, undated, By Melanie Henderson (Box-folder 107/11)
    - One more song, 1987 (Box-folder 108/1-7)
    - Persephone, 1962, 1996, By Charles Burr; Script only (Box-folder 108/8-9)
    - Play on!, 1997 (Box-folder 109/1-12, 110/1-8)
    - Polly, 2000 (Box-folder 110/9)
    - Quasimodo, 1976, By Charles Burr; Script only (Box-folder 111/1)
    - The Ragtime blues, 1976, Script only (Box-folder 111/2-3)
    - Rare breed, 1986, By Melanie Henderson (Box-folder 111/4)
    - Reverend Jenkins' Almost All Colored Orphanage Band, 1987 (Box-folder 111/5-9, 112/1-4)
    - Rodgers and Hart, 1975 (Box-folder 112/5)
    - Saturday laughter, 1998-1999, Other title: Zuma's journey; Renaissance man (Box-folder 112/6-7)
    - St. Louis woman, 1997 (Box-folder 113/1-6)
    - Stormy weather, 2001 (Box-folder 113/7-10)
    - Storyville, 1970s (Box-folder 113/11)
    - Sugar Hill, 1985 (Box-folder 113/12)
    - The three Black kings [ballet], undated, Other title: Les trois rois noirs (Box-folder 113/13)
    - Turned on Broadway [recording], 1982, Royalty statements only (Box-folder 113/14)
    - Walk in my shoes, 1968 (Box-folder 113/15)
  - Performer Projects
    - Brightman, Sarah, 1988 (Box-folder 114/1)
    - Canadian Brass, circa 1992-1990 (Box-folder 114/2-16)
    - Cassidy, Tim, 1975 (Box-folder 115/1)
    - Henderson, Margo, 1969, 1977-1978 and undated (Box-folder 115/2)
    - Horne, Lena, 1983 (Box-folder 115/3)
    - Johnson, Betty, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 115/4)
    - Norman, Jessye, 1993-1998 (Box-folder 115/5)
    - Patinkin, Mandy, 1988 (Box-folder 115/6)
    - Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 115/7)
    - Smith, Alexis, 1975 (Box-folder 115/8)
    - Three Mo' Tenors, 1998 (Box-folder 115/9)
- Personal Correspondence, 1953-2002 (Box 115)
  Letters from family, friends, and notable musical personalities.
  Arranged chronologically or alphabetically by last name of correspondent.
  - 1957-1997 and undated (Box-folder 115/10-12)
  - Allen, Billie, 1968-1969 and undated (Box-folder 115/13)
  - Congratulatory notes, 1958, 1988-1992, Chiefly notes for Ain't misbehavin' and Jelly's last jam (Box-folder 115/14-15)
  - Davis Jr., Sammy, 1956 (Box-folder 115/16)
  - Henderson, Melanie and Denson, 1976-2002 (Box-folder 115/17)
  - Kostelanetz, Andre, 1977 (Box-folder 115/18)
  - Rodgers, Richard, 1975 (Box-folder 115/19)
  - Strayhorn, Billy, 1953 (Box-folder 115/20)
- Business Papers, 1960-2003 (Box 116-117)
  Professional correspondence, contracts, notes, publicity materials, and miscellaneous materials.
  Arranged chronologically or alphabetically by folder title.
  - 1965-2003 and undated (Box-folder 116/1-4)
  - American Eagle Awards, 1993 (Box-folder 116/5)
  - American Musicals Project, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 116/6)
  - BMI, 1986-1995 (Box-folder 116/7)
  - Contact information lists, 1960-1992 and undated (Box-folder 116/8)
  - Do-re-mi-ology, 1987 (Box-folder 117/1)
  - Ellington International Conference, 1998 (Box-folder 117/2)
  - The Juno Company, 1982-1983, Correspondence regarding a Barney Josephson tribute show (Box-folder 117/3)
  - Lena Horne Music Scholarship, 1989 (Box-folder 117/4)
  - MCA Classics, 1987-1997 (Box-folder 117/5)
  - Music rental, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 117/6)
  - Peabody Institute, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 117/7)
  - Quel Else Enterprises, 1978-1989 (Box-folder 117/8)
  - Tony Awards, 1997 (Box-folder 117/9)
  - United Artists Corp., 1975-1976 and undated (Box-folder 117/10)
- Financial Documents, 1964-2003 (Box 117-118)
  Invoices, ledgers, royalties, tax returns, and other personal or business-related items. Projects not identified in above series may have supporting invoices or royalty statements present in these files.
  Arranged alphabetically by file name.
  - AFM pension fund, 1975-2003 (Box-folder 117/11)
  - Computer file indexes, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 117/12)
  - Invoices, 1964-1988 and undated (Box-folder 117/13, 118/1)
  - Ledgers, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 118/2-6)
  - Lu-Mel Music, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 118/7)
  - Pelican Resort and Casino, 1986-1988, 1995 (Box-folder 118/8)
  - Royalties, 1995 (Box-folder 118/9)
  - Royalties and pay stubbs, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 118/10)
  - Tax returns, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 118/11)
- Miscellany, 1935-2000 (Box 119-123, 127-128)
  Personal documents, writings, photographs, realia, posters, and other miscellaneous materials.
  - Awards, 1970s?, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 127/2)
  - Clippings, 1953-1958, 1989, 1994 (Box-folder 119/1)
  - Datebooks and address books, 1975, 1984-1991 (Box 121-123)
  - Miscellany, undated, Includes a portrait drawing of Henderson (Box-folder 127/3)
  - Personal documents, 1956-1996 (Box-folder 119/2)
  - Photographs, 1985-1998 and undated (Box-folder 119/3-6)
  - Posters, undated, Includes several posters for Ain't misbehavin and Jelly's last jam (Box-folder 127/4-5)
  - Programs, 1946-1997 and undated (Box-folder 119/4-10)
  - Realia, 1998 and undated, Ain't misbehavin belt, cap, eyeglasses, metronomes, and a Black Theatre Alliance Award for Play on! (Box 128)
  - Résumés, 1993 and undated (Box-folder 119/11)
  - Scrapbook, 1941-1955 (Box-folder 119/12)
  - Writings, 1935-1939, 1982, 1994-2000 and undated (Box-folder 120/1-6)
- Brick Fleagle Materials, 1930s-1987 (Box 124-125)
  Business papers and photographs formerly in the possession of Henderson's close friend and fellow arranger, Jacob Roger "Brick" Fleagle.
  - Contracts, 1943-1947 (Box-folder 124/1)
  - Correspondence and miscellany, 1973-1977 and undated (Box-folder 124/2)
  - Invoices, 1976-1987 and undated (Box-folder 124/3)
  - Personal documents, 1958, 1971, 1980s (Box-folder 124/4)
  - Photographs, 1930s-1940s and undated
    - Fleagle, alone (Box-folder 125/1)
    - Fleagle, with others, Included: Buck Clayton (Box-folder 125/2)
    - Other performers, Included: Louis Armstrong; Benny Carter; Wayman Carver; Tyree Glenn; Walter Johnson; Claude Jones; John Kirby; Jimmie Lunceford; Sy Oliver; Oran Page; Fats Waller; Ben Webster; Dicky Wells; Rudy Williams (Box-folder 125/3-6)
    - Recording sessions, Included: Buck Clayton; Miles Davis; Jimmy Jones; Tyree Glenn; Cecil Scott; Rex Stewart; Billy Taylor Sr.; Dicky Wells (Box-folder 125/7-8)